Guide to the Franklin Cuthbert Cornell papers, 1857-1938
Cornell, Franklin Cuthbert papers, 1857-1938
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Franklin Cuthbert Cornell papers, 1857-1938.
1-1-456
Franklin Cuthbert Cornell.
2.2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, account books, ledgers, finacial documents, clippings, photogrpahs, legal documents.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Family papers, correspondence, and miscellaneous items concerning Franklin C. Cornell and son, Franklin C. Cornell, Jr.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Family papers, including financial and legal documents, stock certificates, indentures, public foreclosures, judgements, estate settlements (concerning Cornell and his father, Ezra Cornell), title abstracts, promissory notes, cash and farm account books, receipts, checks and check stubs. There are also personal letters, including some from his wife Susannah Pettigrove Cornell; genealogical items; scrapbook of newspaper clippings; and photographs. Miscellaneous items include a manuscript copy of a contract for sale of property by Cornell to Jennie McGraw; accounts paid for Mary Ann Cornell's house; and a Supreme Court brief on the lawsuit brought by Cornell against the Utica, Ithaca, and Elmira Railway Company. The collection also contains papers of Franklin Cornell, Jr., including student notebooks from Cornell University, personal and business correspondence, diaries, and financial and legal documents.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell, Franklin Cuthbert.; Cornell, Ezra, 1807-1874.; Cornell, Franklin Cuthbert.; Cornell, Susannah Pettigrove.; Fiske, Jennie McGraw, 1840-1881.; Cornell University--Students.; Utica, Ithaca, and Elmira Railroad.
Subjects:
Real property--New York (State)--Tompkins County.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Abstract of Title for property of Franklin C. Cornell, Oct. 22, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Articles of Agreement for a sale of property for Franklin C. Cornell to Jennie McGraw. Manuscript copy., Apr. 10, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Indentures, Judgments, Estate Settlements and other legal documents, 1858; 1874-1891 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Indentures, Judgments, Estate Settlements and other legal documents, 1891-1896 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Indenture re A Right of Way between Franklin C. Cornell and Edward and Clarence Wycoff, July 1899 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Legal and Financial Documents of Franklin C. Cornell, 1875-1887 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Legal and Financial Documents of Franklin C. Cornell, 1888-1906 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous financial documents of Franklin C. Cornell, 1865-1900 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous financial documents of Franklin C. Cornell, 1901-1913 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Personal letters to Franklin C. Cornell, 1862-1880 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Personal letters to Franklin C. Cornell, 1881-1907 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Promissory Notes, 1886-1902 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Receipts and checks of F.C. Cornell, 1874-1879 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Receipts and checks of F.C. Cornell, 1880-1913 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Supreme Court Brief re the action brought by Franklin C. Cornell against the Utica, Ithaca and Elmira Railway Company, July 1878 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Abstract of Title for Franklin C. Cornell and Horace L. Smith Estates, Jointly, June 1915 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Accounts paid for Mary Ann Cornell's house by F.C. Cornell, 1880-1881 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- City and County Tax Receipts of Oliver H.P. Cornell, 1890-1897 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Cornell Family Genealogical Items, 1901-1938 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Final Judical Settlement of F.C. Cornell's accounts re the Estate of Ezra Cornell, Nov. 15, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Judicial Settlement of Franklin C. Cornell's Estate. (Including manuscript household inventory, Jan. 1908, and an affidavit for a property fence agreement, July 1908 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Public Foreclosure Notices, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- School Taxes and Property Assessments, 1878-1904 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Stock Certificates, 1876-1904 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Various Record Books of Franklin C. Cornell
  - Employee Time Record Book, Jan. 1859-Jan. 1861 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Union Trust Company Bank Account Book, 1875-188 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Account book for items with Haskin and Todd, 1886 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Ithaca Trust Compant Bank account, 1902-1910 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - One 8 x 10 cost account book, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- F.C. Cornell on the Manning Farm (four photographs) (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Franklin C. Cornell's pocket diaries, 1859-1860 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Checkbooks of F.C. Cornell
  - July 1898-Feb. 1900 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Mar. 1900-Dec. 1901 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Franklin C. Cornell's pocket diaries, 1861; 1867 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Checkbooks of F.C. Cornell
  - The Mercantile Trust Co., New York City, 1881-1883 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - First National Bank of Ithaca, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Book of Check Stubs, 1879-1880 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Ithaca Trust Co., 1896 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Book of Check Stubs, 1875-1876 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Two checkbooks of Franklin C. Cornell
  - One 9" x 4.5" book of checkstubs, 1878 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - One 9" x 5" book of checkstubs, 1894-1895 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- One checkbook of F.C. Cornell, 1893; and one personal notebook (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Checkbooks of F.C. Cornell
  - July 1895-Nov. 1897 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Mar. 1897-July 1898 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Billford of F.C. Cornell, containing assorted currency (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Notebook of Franklin C. Cornell, Jr. (kept as a student at Cornell Univ., Class of 1889, 1885 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Diaries of Franklin C. Cornell, 1881; 1891,; 1894 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Diaries of Franklin C. Cornell, 1903; 1906,; 1907,; 1908 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous papers of F.C. Cornell, Jr., while he was a student at Cornell Univ., Class of 1889, 1884-1887 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Student handbooks of F.C. Cornell, Jr., 1883-1886 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Personal Letters to F.C. Cornell, Jr., 1892-1924 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Legal Documents of F.C. Cornell, Jr., 1899; 1925 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Rents, Taxes and other accounts of F.C. Cornell, Jr., 1910-1912 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Bondholder Committee of Cascadilla School, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- One Brochure: A Case before the Interstate Commerce Commission: F.C. Cornell, Jr. versus Walker D. Hines and Lehigh Valley Railroad Company, c. 1917-1918 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Fixtures, Glassware and Lighting Schedule for new home of Mr. and Mrs. F.C. Cornell, Jr., 1928 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Photographs of F.C. Cornell, Jr., c. 1925 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- F.C. Cornell's Cash Book, J.B. Sprague accounts, 1877-1878 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- F.C. Cornell's Ledger Book, Jan. 1877-Mar. 1881 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- F.C. Cornell's Cash Book, Jan. 1893-Dec. 1894 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- F.C. Cornell's Cash Book, Jan. 1895-Dec. 1896 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- F.C. Cornell's Cash Book, Jan. 1897-Jan. 1901 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- F.C. Cornell's Cash Book, May 1879-Nov. 1877 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- F.C. Cornell's Cash Book, Nov. 1877-May 1879 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- F.C. Cornell's Ledger Book, 1875-1883 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- F.C. Cornell's Farm Account Book, 1859-1871 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- F.C. Cornell's Ledger Book, 1876 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- F.C. Cornell's Ledger Book, Dec. 1874-Apr. 1881 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Cornell Family Genealogical Record and Scrapbook, 1857-1908 (Box 8, Folder 1)